Elena Ortega Frontend Engineer



Senior Frontend Engineer with over 8 years of experience with a passion for creating engaging user experiences. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and various frontend frameworks. Strong problem-solving skills and a keen eye for design.

github.com/elenaorfe
linkedin.com/in/elenaorfe

elenaorfe@gmail.com

EU citizen

# WORK EXPERIENCE -



### Mobile Application for a Client in the Mobility sector

10.2021 - Present

Lead develope

Developed an iOS and Android application using React Native that successfully amassed over 1.5 million users and achieved top ranking as the 1st free iOS app and secured 4th position on Android in Swaden

 $React \ Native \cdot React \ JS \cdot Typescript \cdot Storybook \cdot Graph QL \cdot Parcel \cdot Jest \cdot Datadog \cdot Firebase \cdot Playwright \cdot Fastlane \cdot Gitlab \cdot Scrum \cdot Fastlish$ 

### Web & Mobile Application for a Client in the Prevention of Hazards sector

02.2021 - 09.2021

Fullstack develope

Led the development of a hazard prevention web platform, integrated interactive floor plans, safety guidelines. Provided primary support during the culmination phase, maintaining React Native iOS and Android applications.

ReactJS · Typescript · HTML · Scss · React Native · Firebase · NodeJS · Github · Scrum · Trello · English

# Web Application for a Client in the University sector

10.2020 - 01.2021

Frontend develope

Developed a hate speech detection dashboard to collect and analyze data from multiple social media platforms, incorporating intuitive graphical representations to illustrate hate speech trends and patterns.

 $Angular \cdot \mathsf{Typescript} \cdot \mathsf{HTML} \cdot \mathsf{Scss} \cdot \mathsf{Bootstrap} \cdot \mathsf{D3} \cdot \mathsf{Gitlab} \cdot \mathsf{Scrum} \cdot \mathsf{Jira} \cdot \mathsf{English}$ 

#### Web aplication for a Client in the IoT sector

09.2019 - 10.2020

Frontend develope

Led the migration from AngularJS to Angular and developed new features for a cloud-based measurement data monitoring system.

Angular JS - Angular - Typescript - HTML - Scss - Bootstrap - Responsive Design - Maps API - il8n - Karma - RESTful API - Webpack - Gitlab - Scrum - Jira - English

#### Web aplication for a Client in the IoT sector

06.2019 - 08.2019

Frontend develope

Led a project where I integrated customer-developed API endpoints into a visual map, facilitating the mapping of stores within shopping malls through a custom CMS.

Figma · ReactJS · HTML · Sass · Material UI · Maps API · i18n · RESTful API · Babel · Webpack · Jest · Selenium · Gitlab · Scrum · Trello English

#### Web application for internal use

01.2019 - 05.2019

Frontend develope

Developed a user interface optimized for office needs, delivering tailored information, and integrated the application with various social media APIs.

 $Sketch \cdot Marvel \cdot ReactJS \cdot HTML \cdot Sass \cdot Material \ UI \cdot Bitbucket \cdot Scrum \cdot Trello \cdot English$ 



## Web application for a Client in the Insurance sector

02.2018 - 12.2018

Frontend develope

Led the digital transformation initiative for one of the largest insurance groups in Austria, Central, and Eastern Europe, spearheading the definition, analysis, and implementation of software products.

AngularJS·EC6·HTML·Sass·Bootstrap·Responsive Design·Handlebars·RESTful API·Scrum·Jira·Github·English

# Web application for a Client in the Bank sector

05.2017 - 01.2018

rontend develone

Engaged in the digital transformation of a significant financial group, involving analysis of customer requirements, enhancement of form-based workflows, task estimation, form modeling, and frontend development

#### Web application for a Client in the Bank sector

05 2016 - 04 2017

Frontend develope

Developed a credit card portal, involving analysis of customer requirements and tasks estimation, followed by frontend development.

 $Angular JS \cdot HTML \cdot Sass \cdot Bootstrap \cdot Responsive \ Design \cdot RESTful \ API \cdot Scrum \cdot Jira \cdot Github \cdot English$ 

**R&D Projects** 06.2015 - 04.2

rontend developer

Implemented new features and enhancements for company products within the R&D department, utilizing MV\* architecture, integrating social networks into a multichannel platform, and incorporating a workflow engine into a Java application.

AngularJS · HTML · CSS · Mocha · Facebook API · Twitter API · Yammer API · Java · Oracle D · Activiti · Alfresco · English

#### SIDE PROJECTS

#### Website for Personal Portfolio

01.2024 - Present

nttps://www.eiendorre.com

Created a portfolio website using Next.js with Tailwind CSS, integrated an OpenAl-powered chatbot for natural conversations, and deployed the project on Vercel.

 $\mbox{Next,js} \cdot \mbox{Typescript} \cdot \mbox{Tailwind} \cdot \mbox{Sass} \cdot \mbox{Vercel} \cdot \mbox{ally} \cdot \mbox{OpenAl API} \cdot \mbox{D3}$ 

# Website for an architecture and interior design studio

07.2021 - Present

https://www.doscestudio.com

Developed a website with a headless WordPress CMS, integrated with Next,js with Tailwind CSS, and deployment on Vercel.

 $\label{eq:Next_solution} Next.js \cdot Typescript \cdot Tailwind \cdot GraphQL \cdot Wordpress \cdot Web \\ hosting \cdot ally \cdot OpenAl \ API \cdot D3$ 

## Website for an art curator

09.2020 - Present

https://www.marinariera.com

Developed a website with a headless WordPress CMS, integrated with Next, is with Tailwind CSS, and deployment on Vercel.

 $\label{eq:loss_problem} Next.js \cdot Typescript \cdot Tailwind \cdot GraphQL \cdot Wordpress \cdot Webhosting \cdot ally \cdot OpenAl \ API \cdot D3$ 

# Website for a scout association

01.2019

nttps://www.gs125.com

Developed a WordPress plugin for a website.

PHP · Wordpress · Bootstrap · Web hosting

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**Frontend · React Native · ReactJS · Typescript ·

Storybook · GraphQL · HTML · Angular · Angular JS · Maps API · il8n · RESTful API · Sass · Material UI · Javascript · Next.js · OpenAl API infrastructure · Parcel · Firebase · Fastlane · Vercel testing · Jest · Playwright tool · Datadog · il8n style · Scss · Bootstrap · D3 · Responsive Design · Sass · Material UI · CSS · Mocha · Tailwind runtime · NodeJS SkillType.Testing · Karma · Jest · Selenium SkillType.Infrastructure · Webpack accessibility · ally cms · Wordpress

#### **EDUCATION**

Master in IoT, Domotics and Smart Cities

Salamanca

Spanish English

German

**Erasmus Program** Dresde 2013-20

**Bachelor Degree in Industrial Engineering**Malaga

2015

LANGUAGES

EANOGACES